What is life ?
It is the beginning of death .
What is death ?
It is the end of life .
What is existence ?
It is the continuity of blood .
What is blood ?
It is the reason to exist !
[ AT MIDNIGHT I 'LL TAKE YOUR SOUL ]
I wish you a terrible evening ,
my brave little friends .
Remember these words :
Those of you who have been watching a funeral ,
and seen the pale face of a corpse .
Those of you who don 't believe in wandering ghosts
when you leave this theatre ...
and have to walk in the dark streets ...
alone ...
There is still time .
Don 't watch this movie !
Go home !
Too late .
You 've not believed .
You want to show a courage that doesn 't exist ?
Then , stay !
Suffer !
Watch ...
" At Midnight I 'll Take Your Soul ! "
Oh , Carlos , why did you leave me ? Why ?
Be brave , Mrs. Joana .
My condolences , Mrs. Joana .
You can be sure that I provided the best of my services .
Excuse me ...
Bring my lunch , Lenita .
Coming , Joe .
That funeral made me hungry ...
I 'm thinking of double my fee to follow the burial .
I 'm sick and tired of all that crying .
It 's your job , Joe . You should take care of your clients .
Look , I 'm tired of all these people
Hey , where 's the meat ?
Not today . Did you forgot that today is Holy Friday ?
What do I care if it 's Holy or Evil Friday ?
I 'll get what I want and none religious fanatic will stop me .
I 'll eat meat today , even if it 's human flesh !
Watch out , Joe ! The devil may be tempting you !
If I meet him , I 'll invite him for dinner .
Oh , what a pleasant surprise ! What do you want ?
Terezinha insisted on visiting Lenita and invite her to the procession .
I think it is no use ... But ...
I will talk to her .
As you wish . - Where are you going , Joe ?
Well ... I want to buy a lamb .
Save for Easter ?
No , to eat today !
I 'll go down stairs a little , Lenita .
I know who you saw ! It 's that little woman .
You think I didn 't notice the way you looked at her this afternoon ?
You know that I hate melodramatics !
I 'm not a woman to be treated this way , Joe !
And stop bothering that girl .
At least have some respect to your friendship with Antônio .
You have talked enough .
Antônio will be there soon .
I don 't want to stay there too long .
Good evening .
Good evening . - Good evening
Where are you going ?
I 'm taking Terezinha to Clemencia and Antônio will pick her up later .
What a coincidence !
I 'm going there too .
Don 't worry . I 'll take her .
Antônio may not like that , Sr. Joe .
Well ... Antônio is my best friend , right ?
So itseems .
You decide , Terezinha .
Well , if you have another appointment ...
Ah , but he does . Don 'tyou , Aristides ?
You have a very important appointment . Isn 't truth ?
Yes . Now I remembered . I do have an appointment , yes .
I 'll appreciate if you could take her .
Good night , Terezinha .
Good night . - Good night .
Thanks for allowing me to walk with you .
I don 't see a reason to thank me .
Will Antônio take long to pick you up ?
Not , he said that he would come soon .
Lucky man .
You know that I suffer with Antônio 's luck having you as his fiancée ?
I think you 're exaggerating .
I think I 'm a happy woman for having the love of Antônio .
Either you are silly , or want to play with me .
You know you aren 't the woman for Antônio .
You are the woman for me !
Take your hands off me , Joe ! You 're hurting me !
I want to see if your lips are so defiant as your words !
You have the fangs of a snake ...
and the face of an angel .
Antônio wouldn 't know about this .
But I ask you for not let this scene happen again
Very well , I 'll go with you .
Thanks . I 'd rather go alone .
Bring some wine , Maria .
Ranulfo .
Yes , Mr. Joe !
Go to my house and ask Lenita to send me the lamb .
I 'll be back soon .
It looks like a good game . Very good .
There 's room for one more ?
Thanks ! You 're very kind .
Maria , more wine .
That man scares me , Mr. Francisco !
Don 't let him see it , or things gonna be worse .
I pass .
I double .
The bet are too high for me , too .
Looks like ... just you and me .
Will you go on ?
I double .
Brave man .
A real man got to be like this :
All ... or nothing .
I pay a thousand to see your cards .
But , I-I ... d-don 't have any more money .
No ? Then show me your cards .
It 's ... three kings .
Bad luck , my friend .
- Four aces . - It is not possible !
Let go of the money , man !
I can 't . I need the money !
Let go of the money !
My hand , my hand ...
As I said : I like brave men !
Call the doctor .
I 'll pay for the bill . to .
Ah , you 're my witnesses :
It was an accident .
Here 's the meat , Mr. Joe .
Excellent , just in time .
A scene like that can make everyone hunger , right ?
You , Bonifácio . You look hungry .
Have a piece of this lamb .
No , thanks , I don 't want it .
Come here , boy !
Have a bite ... It 's very good .
- Today is a holy day , Mr. Joe . I can 't eat meat . - Eat it !
Please ...
Eat it !
Ah , the doctor is here !
What 's happening here ?
An unfortunate accident , doctor .
The victim is Zerequiel .
Take good care of him and I 'll pay all the bills .
Your kindness knows no bounds , Joe .
Thank you .
More wine , Maria !
Better take him to the hospital .
Very well .
You act as if you 're afraid of me .
No , Mr. Joe . I have other customers to take care .
Leave them to Chico , heh ?
Tonight you work only for me , what do you think ?
What does he want with my niece ?
Is no one here brave enough to face this man ?
- Then why don 't you ? - That 's what I 'll do !
Joe , leave the girl alone !
And who 's going to make me leave her ?
I am , you emissary of Satan !
Stop , Joe , stop ! You 're going to kill the poor man !
Have mercy , Joe ! Mercy ...
I have enough work with those who die of natural causes .
You can be sure :
I 'll charge double to bury anyone I kill !
- Let 's go home , Joe . - Let 's go .
Oh , I 'm going to the crossroads by the graveyard ...
Anyone wants to follow me ?
I was passing by with Terezinha when I heard the screams .
What happened , Antônio ?
- It 's all right now . - Thank goodness .
By the way , Antônio ,
let 's take a rain check on that fishing .
It 's up to you .
I 'm going to take Terezinha home . Want to come along ?
But , Antônio , he has to go home . Lenita is all alone .
A woman who can 't bear a child needs no care .
We 'll talk tomorrow , Antônio .
- Good night . - Good night .
Terezinha rejects me because the existence of Lenita .
Is life worth living if there 's no son to continue the bloodline ?
What 's one mistress among so many women ?
Lenita has to die ...
I 'm so sorry about what happened .
Will you forgive me ? Tell me you aren 't angry with me ...
It 's all right , Lenita .
You make me so happy ! I can 't help but feel jealous .
I want to make you happy , my love !
Your wish will be fulfilled .
You 're going to make me very happy .
This will be a very amusing show !
A woman must belong to only one man .
Since you 're of no use to me ,
I 'll do you a favor and spare you of the sin of needing another man .
Is your life worth living If you can 't bear a child ...
to continue your bloodline ?
You wouldn 't be an obstacle to the only truth of the existence .
Terezinha will be mine ...
and from her womb my lineage will continue .
I 'll have the honor of seeing you die before my eyes .
Pity ... You seemed so unique
Now there you are , in the painful affliction of death !
You suffer , because you can 't scream !
Lenita , now you leave me and become the death 's mistress .
It was a great show ! Thank you !
Let 's make sure the doctor takes good care of you .
There 's nothing more to do . She was bitten by a spider .
Poor girl . It must have been so painful .
I 'll file the report for the police officer .
Very well , doctor . I 'll take care of the rest .
Well , goodbye .
I want to go home , I want to go home ... - Be quiet , boy , or I 'll beat you !
Quiet !
- Ah , you ... - I want to go ...
Don 't abuse your child !
He 's the continuity of your blood .
A real man doesn 't cry .
Take your son ... but don 't hurt him .
It 's been fifteen days since Lenita died .
I miss her very much .
Of course you do . Lenita loved you very much ,
and I know that you loved her too .
Yes . One day everything comes to an end .
We are born ... and then die .
That 's life . We have got to accept that .
Ah ... What if we go fishing tomorrow ?
Okay .
Oh , Joe , one more thing .
- What ? - Do you want to visit the gypsy with us ?
Do what ?
Terezinha insisted . She wants to know her future .
You know , women about to get married ...
- And you , do you want to go ? - Well , we always have some doubt , right ?
I 'll go .
It 'll be fun to see two superstitious under the spell of a witch .
- Good evening !
- Good evening . - Good evening .
Come in , my children !
Make yourselves at home . Have a seat .
- I 'd like to know ... - Say no more !
Look into my eyes , and I 'll tell you your future .
Beware , my child ! Beware
Happiness is yours .
But don 't forget who you love , and everything will be right .
Otherwise there will be death ... misfortune ...
Read my future now . Who knows , it may be a little better
Your lifeline ends right here !
Don 't think of your earthly life , and everything will go well .
Fulfill your soul .
Don 't allow the earth to receive your body in broad daylight .
Your salvation demands That you be buried at midnight !
Stop that nonsense , you old witch !
Forgive me , but I can 't stand this foolishness .
ln your eyes I see your fate .
You 'll pay for your sins ,
and when the time comes , you 'll suffer the horrors of hell !
You go to hell !
Let 's go home , Terezinha . How much ?
You don 't have to pay me .
The laws of the supernatural forbid me to accept money when death is foretold .
Go , my children . Beware .
Well , Terezinha , let 's forget that gypsy woman
and think about what to do tomorrow .
I know . The hard work will be all mine .
You 'll have a good night 's sleep , and want me to wake you up , right ?
So , it 's all set ? Let 's go , Antônio .
- Good night , darling . - Good night .
Good night .
I don 't know what 's wrong with me . I feel restless .
A good bath will cure that .
- Come over , and have a drink with me . - Very well .
Try this wine , Joe . I think you 'll like it .
Drinking is the best way to ward off the evil spirits .
As if you believed in such things ...
lf I believe it or not , in fact I must agree with the believers .
Frankly , I don 't understand you , Joe .
Where does all your disbelief came from ?
It 's like a rebellion . Against what ?
You have a lot to learn , Antônio .
I can 't disbelieve , when I never had any belief .
To believe in what ? ln a symbol ?
ln an non-existent force created by ignorance ?
Yes , I 'm a rebel ... against fools like you ,
who fear what you don 't see ,
and become slaves to that which really exists : life !
I don 't know why I should fear life .
Because it 's life that makes your flesh throb .
Life feeds your feelings , and if you aren 't strong ...
not to fight it , you 'll be dominated , and will suffer .
Take a look at your people
Why do they fear me ?
Because I use black clothes ? Because I believe in myself ?
Because I laugh at their beliefs ?
No . Because I 'm stronger than then , and I have brain ...
enough to dominate whoever that it is .
They 're weak , because they 're enslaved by what they don 't know .
I 'm free . Therefore , I 'm stronger .
You may have your reasons , but I 'm happy the way I am .
I love Terezinha and I know she loves me .
I don 't have any inner conflict .
I want only to marry her , and I know that will happen soon .
We like the same things . I feel good believing in God .
I can 't be a rebel against everyone .
You know , Terezinha is like an angel .
We 're going to remodel this house ...
and live here together for the rest of our lives .
That is my biggest desire .
What was all that faith good for ?
I 'm stronger than you !
Antônio ! Antônio !
Antônio ? Antô ...
I don 't know , Barretos . It was quite a shock to me .
Believe me , I would give my own life for Antônio 's .
Don 't think that I 'm accusing you .
But you were the last person to see him alive ,
so you must remain a suspect until we have an autopsy
Excuse me ...
Commissioner , the doctor needs you .
Excuse me . I must go to the morgue .
I 'm going to my funerary , and later I 'll meet you there .
Very well .
" ln the name of the Father , the Son and the Holy Spirit " .
Antônio ! Antônio !
Antônio ! ...
Murderer !
Damn you ! Murderer !
Calm down ... Take her outside .
You killed Antônio ! Murderer !
Try to calm her down .
Close the casket .
So soon we won 't forget Antônio 's funeral .
They say he was buried at midnight to save his soul .
He must have something wrong with him , because he was Joe 's friend .
We should run that man out of town !
He 's got an eye for Terezinha ...
And the girl is at home all alone .
Her father went to the city to see his wife at the hospital .
Look who 's here .
Maria , bring me a bottle of wine .
Hey , did you change your name to Maria ?
Leave the bottle there ; put there , old man ! Leave it !
I asked her to serve me . I 'm waiting , girl .
Come here .
How much for the bird ?
But , it 's not for sale .
What 's the price ?
Well , I don 't know . I don 't know .
Is two thousand enough ?
Great ... great !
I 'll take the bird .
We 'll talk some other day .
What now ?
You never seen a little bird ?
Or shall I take the measurements for your coffins ?
Oh , what do you want here so late ?
Don 't be afraid . I brought you a present .
Thank you . Good night .
Hold on , girl . Show some manners .
Please , Joe . What will the neighbors think ?
Don 't worry .
They will not think anything .
This people don 't have the guts to go out in the streets at this hour .
What are you going to do with the bird ?
Throw it away . You don 't want to accept my present .
Oh , no ! Poor thing !
He must be hungry , poor one .
I knew you had a kind heart .
Please , you 're hurting me !
- You ... - Have mercy ...
- You wouldn 't treat Antônio like that . - Go away !
Don 't talk about Antônio . Go away !
After all I did to rid you of that fool ,
you tell me to go away ?
Don 't touch me !
Respect me , Joe .
- You ain 't easy . But I like the hard way . - No ! No !
I want you to be mine . And I always get what I want .
No ! Help !
No ! No !
Snake from hell .
You 'll be very quiet .
Help !
No ! No !
Help ! Help !
Mercy !
That 's right , this is the way I like it .
You 'll give me the son I want .
You 've ruined me , Joe . I can 't go on living .
I 'm going to kill myself .
It 's always like that ...
All women say the same thing .
Later they regret it .
Life is good , it 's not worth trading for death .
I 'll be back some other time , Terezinha .
I 'll kill myself , Joe , but I promise you 'll not have any peace
You killed Antônio and he was buried at midnight .
and at midnight , Joe , you 'll know fear , because I 'll come to take your soul !
Wherever you take me , if there are women like you ,
I 'll be happy to go !
Excuse me ...
Today is my lucky day .
The devil himself is here , right ?
Spirits !
Do you hear me ?
Which of you is going to take my soul ?
Behold ... I 'm waiting !
Arise ! Out of your graves ...
and take me straight to hell !
Can 't you hear me ?
Can 't you hear me ? Take me straight to hell !
Antônio !
I possessed Terezinha .
What will you do to me ?
Nothing !
Because you no longer exist !
You 're dead !
Dead !
Your hour is coming . Your end is near .
You 'll feel the burden of your sins .
Shut up ,
old witch .
I 'll make your coffin .
Laughs the living !
Mock the dead !
You 'll live the horrors from hell !
[ With these few lines , I ask my parents For for give ness , for my condemnable act . ]
[ There 's nobody to blame in this tragedy , I couldn 't support the weight on my shoulders . ]
[ lf must have a sentence for the reason of my death , ]
[ I 'll be the judge , and wherever I may be , justice will be fulfilled . Terezinha ]
How can we charge him ,
if she left a note explaining why she did it ?
There 's something strange here .
I can 't figure why she didn 't put the blame on Coffin Joe
ldiot !
She had the courage to kill herself .
Strange ... she didn 't blame me .
Let his soul rest in peace .
Her father insisted she be buried next to Antônio .
[ Through this letter , I came to the autorities ... ]
[ to request urgent autorization ... ]
[ to proceed a new autopsy on Antônio 's corpse . ]
[ Thinking about the last events occurred in this city , ]
[ I came to believe that we are dealing with ... ]
[ homi ... ]
Good evening , doctor
Did I frighten you ?
Hmm ... savior of mankind !
But the people doesn 't care for that .
The report is only a formality .
Sorry I 'm so curious to read your work , but ...
As they say , eyes are made for seeing .
What are you trying to do , Joe ?
Nothing .
Just making sure your eyes don 't see what they shouldn 't
Sorry , doctor .
You make me so happy ! I can 't help but feel jealous .
I want so much to make you happy !
We 're going to remodel this house and live here to get her for the rest of our lives .
At midnight , Joe , you 'll know fear , because I 'll come to take your soul !
- What are you trying to do , Joe ? - I want to make you happy !
Together , for the rest of our lives .
I 'll come to take your soul !
- What are you trying to do , Joe ? - Make you happy !
- What are you trying to do , Joe ? - Make you happy
For the rest of our lives .
I 'll come to take your soul !
- What are you trying to do , Joe ? - Make you happy !
Lenita !
Antônio !
Rodolfo !
You 're all dead .
I did it for you , Terezinha .
You 've forsaken me .
You didn 't give me a son .
You 've doomed my bloodline to extinction .
I want a son !
Damn you ! Curse your faith !
Terezinha !
Come out of nowhere ...
and punish the crime of my passion !
Torture my flesh !
Take my soul !
Why don 't you come ?
You 're a ghost from the past .
Yet , I feel the blood boiling in my veins .
I 'm alive !
Alive , understood ?
You are dead !
Rotted !
Eaten by worms !
HEAVEN !
HELL !
REINCARNATION !
The power of faith !
Symbol of ignorance !
Where are you , Satan ?
Lies ! Lies !
May the earth crack open !
May the skies be torn !
I want the end of the world !
I challenge your power !
I deny your existence !
Nothing exists . Only life
Nothing 's stronger than my disbelief
Destroy me ! I have no faith .
I want the proof of the punishment !
Lies !
What an unfortunate accident . A sad loss for our town .
Such is life . Excuse me , gentlemen .
Evidence ! Evidence , my friends .
Well , it 's nine o 'clock .
Today is Day of the Dead . Time to go home .
Yes . The night is pitch black .
I should be going , too .
- See you tomorrow . - See you tomorrow
What 's the hurry , fell as ?
Today is the Day of the Dead . We shouldn 't be out .
To believe such ridiculous nonsense .
It 's not nonsense , Mr. Joe .
Last year Gumercindo scoffed , and had the punishment .
He saw the wandering ghosts .
It 's true , Mr. Joe . You shouldn 't make fun tonight .
Or you 'll may watch the Procession of the Dead
Procession of the Dead ... It 's a bedtime story for children .
Everyone has a right to their own beliefs .
Okay then , you win !
No more talk of that .
Now you won 't go home . Stay and have a drink with me , right ?
Anyone turning me down ?
Not at all , Mr. Joe .
I like men with strong opinions .
Chico , drinks for everyone .
Don 't you want a drink , fell as ?
Come , have a drink ! Drink !
Maria .
Here 's a small gift for being so kind to me .
No , Mr. Joe , I can 't accept it . Look , my uncle is coming .
- Good evening . - Good evening .
I 'm here to pick you up , Maria . It 's very late .
I was just about to leave , if Bonifácio can follow me .
Were you paid today ?
No , uncle , Mr. Joe gave it to me as a gift .
Take your money back ! My niece will take no gift from you .
I gave her the money , and I want her to have it .
if you 'll not take it back , it stays right here .
Let 's go , Maria .
Old man .
Pick up that money !
Pick up that money ! NOW !
Enough ! This man has pushed us around for too long !
Time to settle it for good !
I 'll not pick up that money ! I 'll not pick up that money !
What will you do to me now ?
What will you do to me now , Coffin Joe ?
I 'll not pick up that money , do you understand , Joe do Caixão ?
I 'll not pick up that money !
Uncle , uncle ...
Pick up that money !
I 'm going to count to three ...
One ...
Two ...
THREE !
Give it to your niece .
Good evening , gentlemen .
It 's all closed in this town . This is the only place I found open .
There was nowhere I could go for information .
How can we help you , ma 'am ?
I 'd like to know where the Queiroz family 's house is .
I 'm here to visit her , but there was no one to pick me up at the station ,
because I missed the afternoon train .
But , lady , Mrs. Matilde lives farfrom here ...
Her house is beyond the cemetery .
But could anyone of you take me there ?
Not tonight , you 'll not find anyone .
I 'm willing to pay .
No money in the world would be enough .
Today is Day of the Dead , and no one goes out at this hour .
What am I going to do ?
I don 't know anyone in town and , for what I saw , there are no hotels .
Don 't worry .
Lf you 'll allow me , I 'd be honored to escort you .
I 'm at your service .
I appreciate it , gentleman . I don 't know how could I thank you .
My reward is to walk with such a beautiful lady .
You are very kind .
You could stay at my place tonight and I 'll take you tomorrow .
Thanks . But I 'd rather go tonight .
Any other question , gentlemen ?
If any of you think yourselves brave enough
I 'll gladly step aside .
Let 's go ?
Ah , by the way ...
lf I meet a corpse along the way ,
I 'll send him your regards !
I noticed that the people here are very superstitious .
They try to cover their fear ; they 're all a bunch of cowards
- Aren 't you afraid ? - Of spirits from beyond ?
I may fearsome of the living , but I can protect my self from them .
Well , you 'll have to admit that the night is really cold and dark
A night like any other .
How many births and deaths are happening this very night ?
You 're right ; I don 't believe in this nonsense , either ...
Don 't be frightened . It 's the old witch !
Beware !
Beware of the DEAD !
Go to hell , sorceress !
When you hear the wind blowing over the trees ,
it 'll not be the wind ... but the wandering ghosts .
Don 't wait until midnight .
When you see a black cat in your path , it 'll be the Devil .
When you hear footsteps and there 's no one behind you ,
it 'll be the damnation of your soul .
When you hear the death call of the owl ,
it 'll be the harbinger of your end .
Don 't wait until midnight .
When you see light in your path ,
it 'll be the candles of the Procession of the Dead .
RUN AWAY !
Because they 'll come for your soul !
My God , what a horrible laughter !
I 'll take care of you on my way back , witch !
Let 's go , my dear .
Well , here we are , and now I bid you farewell .
Butwhy ? Would you like come in ?
Thank you .
I don 't get along with your aunt , and I 'd rather not be seen by her .
Well , I hope to see you again before I go .
Don 't worry . I 'll make sure of that .
My name is Marta Queiroz .
I am Joe ... to my friends .
Hmm , looks like someone is coming . I should go .
- So long , Marta . - Good night , Joe .
She 's pretty .
If I play right , she won 't escape me .
When you hear the wind blowing over the trees ,
it 'll not be the wind ... but the wandering ghosts .
When you see a black cat in your path , it 'll be the Devil .
Don 't wait until midnight .
Who 's following me ?
Who wants to play with me ?
Look out ! Look out ! I 'll shoot !
When you hear footsteps and there 's no one behind you ,
it 'll be the damnation of your soul .
Don 't wait until midnight .
I must be impressionable tonight . It was only an owl .
When you hear the death call of the owl ,
it 'll be the harbinger of your end .
Don 't wait until midnight .
A light ?
I 'm safe ! I 'm safe !
It 'll be the candles of the Procession of the Dead .
No , no ... it can 't be real !
It must be an hallucination !
No , no ... no !
Lies !
No , no ...
They are dead ! DEAD !
I know it ... I KNOW IT !
No ... I must see them . I must see them !
I must see them .
No ... I don 't believe it ! I DON 'T BELIEVE IT !
Lies ! Lies ! Lies !
There was a terrible noise . I was too frightened to go alone .
Something must have happened here .
[ THE END ]